Hello English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco and I'm Erica.
And today we're
bringing you another great
lesson and this time
we're going to be shopping.
That's right. Actually
a lot of our users
asked for some lessons
about shopping, right?
Exactly. And I think one
of the most important
things when you go
shopping is to get a good price.
That's right. So we're going to
be teaching you how to bargain.
So Marco, you just
mentioned a really great word.
Let's look at it in
vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
All right. So we're going to
preview the word bargain today.
Bargain. Bargain.
Now this is an interesting word
because it's a verb and noun.
That's right.
So a bargain is a good price, right?
Okay. So a bargain is a good price.
Yeah. This t-shirt was a bargain.
I only paid a dollar for it.
Okay. So that is
a bargain. Yeah.
But to bargain as a verb.
To try and get a good price.
So it's very similar to negotiate.
Yeah. So I would say it costs $100.
And then I would say maybe
it no, I'll give you 50, 75.
And then I'll say 60, et cetera, et cetera.
And that's to bargain, right?
Yep. Okay. So we're going to be bargaining.
Let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time
as we have a woman
bargaining in a store, right?
That's right.
Hello, may help you? Yeah.
This dress is really nice. How much is it?
That one is $150. $150.
What about this other one over here?
That's $140.
That's a piece of house in my price range.
Can you give me a better deal?
This is an exclusive design by Damarkel.
It's a bargain at that price.
Well, I don't know. I think I'll shop
around. Okay. Okay. How about $100?
That's still more than I want to spend.
What if I take post dresses?
Okay. I can give you a special discount
just because you seem like a nice person.
$190 for both. I don't know.
Still a bit pricey. Thanks anyway.
Okay. My final
price. $100 for both.
That's two for the price of
one, and that's my last offer.
Great. You close the deal.
All right. That was some good
bargaining skills right there. Yeah.
And you know what?
She used a lot of good
language to get a
cheaper price, didn't she?
Yeah. Yeah. That was good. So let's take a
look at this language in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay. The first word we
have in language takeaway
today, price range,
price range, price range.
Price range. Price range.
What does that mean exactly?
So price range is the
minimum and the maximum that
you're willing to spend or a
thing that you want to buy.
Exactly. So in the dialogue we
heard, it's out of my price range.
It's more than I can spend.
More than I could spend. Yeah.
Okay. Okay. Let's look at our next word.
Shop around.
Shop around. Shop around. Shop around.
So she said, I think I'll shop around.
Right.
So she wants to check in a few other
stores to see if there's a better price.
If I shop around, I'm going and
trying to compare prices maybe.
Exactly. This is a really good
shopping technique. Yeah, it is. Yep.
Okay. And let's look at
our last word, pricey. Pricey.
Pricey. Pricey.
So something that's pricey is expensive.
Expensive. Yep. This is a more sort
of informal way of saying expensive.
Exactly. So instead of saying,
wow, that car is really expensive.
It's really pricey.
It's really pricey. Yeah.
Okay. Let's listen to
our dialogue for the
second time and it's
going to be slow down a bit.
So you'll understand some of
these great words a little bit better.
Hello. May I help you? Yeah.
This dress is really nice. How much is it?
That one is $150. $150.
What about this other one over here?
That's $140. Mm. That's a bit out of my
price range. Can you give me a better deal?
This is an exclusive design by Damarko.
It's a bargain at that price.
Mm. Well, I don't know.
I think I'll shop around.
Okay. Okay. How about $100?
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
What if I take both dresses?
Okay. I can give you a special discount
just because you seem like a nice person.
$190 for both. I don't know.
It's still a bit pricey. Thanks anyway.
Okay. My final
price. $100 for both.
That's two for the price
of one. That's my last offer.
Great. You've got to deal.
So we've covered the
language in this dialogue.
Now let's take a look at some of
the phrases in putting it together.
Putting it together.
So, Marko, in this
dialogue there's a lot
of really useful phrases
to help you get a better
price when you shop, right?
Exactly. So the first one we have
is, can you give me a better deal?
Can you give me a better deal?
So if I'm shopping and
something is too expensive,
I would use this sentence
with the shopkeeper.
Yeah. So you might say, hey,
this is out of my price range.
Could you give me a better deal?
Can you give me a better deal? Yeah.
Okay. We have some examples of, can
you give me a better deal? Let's listen.
Example one.
I really like this shirt, but it's too
expensive. Can you give me a better deal?
Example two.
Can you give me a better price on this car?
I really don't have that much money.
So you can see here that you can
say, can you give me a better deal?
Or can you give me a better price?
All right.
Let's take a look at the next phrase.
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
So if the seller suggests a
really high price, you can say.
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
So basically you're telling the shopkeeper?
Still too expensive.
You still don't want to spend that much.
All right.
Let's take a look at our last phrase.
That's my last offer.
Now this could work both ways.
It could be the shopkeeper
that's telling you that.
That's my lowest price.
Right.
Or you could say, that's my last offer.
That's my highest
price if you are buying it.
Right.
Because sometimes when
you're bargaining, the
shopkeeper will say, all
right, what's your best offer?
How much will you pay?
$100.
That's my final offer.
Exactly.
All right.
So we've looked at a lot
of great phrases and words.
And now you're ready to bargain and also
listen to this dialogue for the third time.
And then we'll come
back and talk some more.
Hello, may help you?
Yeah.
This dress is really nice.
How much is it?
That one is $150.
$150.
What about this other one over here?
That's $140.
Um, that's a piece of
house in my price range.
Can you give me a better deal?
This is an exclusive design by Damarco.
It's a bargain at that price.
Well, I don't know.
I think I'll shop around.
Okay.
How about $100?
That's still more than I want to spend.
What if I take both dresses?
Okay.
I can give you a special discount just
because you seem like a nice person.
$190 for both.
Well, I don't know.
Still a bit pricey.
Thanks anyway.
Okay.
My final price.
$100 for both.
That's two for the price of one.
And that's my last offer.
Great.
You cost a deal.
All right.
So I know that in Canada, it's not
really common to bargain, right?
No.
It really isn't like even when you go to
the market to buy fruits and vegetables.
It's very, very rare to
bargain with the shop.
Mm-hmm.
How about an Ecuador?
In Ecuador, you definitely bargain.
Really?
Well, if you go to the
mall, for example, or if
you go to a supermarket, of
course you wouldn't really bargain.
Yeah.
Unless maybe you go to a small store
or you go to one of the local markets.
Yep.
Then it's more common to bargain.
Yeah.
And you have to because
people expect you to bargain.
Really?
Yeah.
And many countries in the world,
bargaining is almost like an art.
Yeah.
That's true.
Actually, Marco, you are
an excellent bargain artist.
Yeah.
I've been known to bargain
with the shopkeepers.
I've been known to bargain a little
bit with the shopkeepers in helping out.
A little bit.
I mean, you've got better prices
than I can even imagine getting.
Yeah.
That's a good story.
Maybe we'll get JP to go to our
comment section and tell you about that.
Yeah.
So we want to know about your countries.
Is it common to bargain?
Do you really do it?
Is it OK or when is it OK?
Yes.
Tell us.
Visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
Tell us about your
country's bargaining customs.
And also leave your questions there for us.
Exactly.
We'll be there to answer them.
But until then, we got to go so.
Goodbye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]